the Galaxy s25 Ultra is the most
enticing phone that Samsung has ever
made the thing is addictively delightful
to use I'd say this is the closest phone
has ever come to being an iPhone killer
but at the same time should you actually
go out and buy one right now in most
cases I would say no let me explain why
so on one hand it's actually kind of
hard to describe just how much I love
using this thing I mean just from a
technical materials perspective the
glass being used on the front and back
the now stronger Titanium on the body
this is one tough phone I've been
specifically using it without a case to
test it and so far at least it's been in
a camera bag it's been in backpacks
pockets it's been embedded into our
table during a failed intro I even
painfully sat here rubbing my wedding
ring against it and there is a little
more dust collection than I would like
but zero in the way of damage only thing
that has unfortunately marked it is a
pretty nasty meter and a half drop
straight onto concrete but when I saw
that happen I was bracing myself for a
lot worse than this the battery life is
even better than last year it's just
under 9 hours of Total screen on time
per charge when the screen is set to the
default 10 P which means I'm reaching
the end of my days with 30 to 40% left
in the tank consistently but also is
this not just like gorgeous it's like
the precise looking design of the phone
paired with this almost borderless
display that's so vibrant so crisp and
almost immune to Reflections to the
point where you don't even need to turn
the brightness High to see it clearly
all topped off with easily Samsung's
most beautiful software ever actually
I'll tell you how you know that Samsung
has hit the nail on the head with this
one ui7 Android skin drisha why and
lifetime iPhone user picked this phone
up for the first time rolled it around
in her hands scrolled for 5 minutes she
looked at me and she said you know what
I actually like this she has never said
that before to me in the 5 years that
we've been together but I can kind of
see why she said it here it feels like
this software is specifically designed
to feel familiar to an iPhone user the
icons and widgets are now more in line
than ever the multitasking page is now
practically identical the way that you
can Now swipe down from the right to
pull up your Control Center and then
swipe down from the left to open a
separate notifications tray the way that
you customize your lock screen is like
okay copy my homework and don't even
worry about changing it would it be even
better if Samsung had been more original
maybe but here's the thing I actually
think Samsung is pulling it off better
than Apple I love how now when I'm
browsing the settings I can just type
approximately what a setting might be
you know in human language and the phone
understands what I'm looking for this
used to be such a pain before cuz you
need to remember exactly what the phone
labels each specific setting as if you
want to find it the Samsung photo
gallery feels way more intuitive than
Apples who's honestly just massacred
their photos app in iOS 18 it's also way
more intelligent like when I'm searching
for past pictures it is spot-on it
understands the assignment every time
people always talk about maximum
brightness oh dear God but I really like
how dim the minimum brightness on this
gets it's less strenuous on your eyes
just before bed and the thing is just so
fast you know the iPhone always has this
implicit reputation as the smooth one
the one that does animations right well
I don't actually think that's the case
anymore this Samsung feels blazing fast
thanks to each animation being both very
smooth like the iPhone while also being
tuned to be quicker than Apples it gives
the phone this feeling of
instantaneousness that actually makes
the Iphone feel slow by comparison so
why on Earth would I not recommend that
you run out and you buy this thing right
now okay there's a few reasons in this
moment you can get a Galaxy s24 Ultra
brand spanking you for $800 whereas this
is a $1,300 phone it's like 60% more
expensive okay that's fine that happens
every year and usually I am very much on
the side of we use our phones so much
why not just buy the latest one if you
can afford it but this is one of the
first cases where I'm still not
convinced first of all I feel like I've
made it pretty clear just how much I
love Samsung's new Android skin but you
should be getting practically the full
one ui7 feature set on the s24 ultra 2
this new phone has an even faster chip
than last year like significantly faster
just to give you an idea we ran a
30-minute stress test on this s25 Ultra
the s24 ultra before it and the iPhone
16 Pro Max and while the s25 ultra does
have the lowest stability meaning that
over the course of that 30 minutes it
lost the most performance compared to
where it started because of how high its
starting point was even its lowest
performance is still about 25% faster
than the lowest of the other two phones
but the thing is I can't find a way to
actually use that power in my day-to-day
life like I said the phone does just
feel faster than last year but that's
just the software that's not because of
the Chip And in terms of games I wish
the landscape was different I wish the
top 50 games on the Play Store were all
just super graphically intense massive
3d worlds but they're not to appeal to
the widest pool of people most mobile
games are developed to run on $100
phones so finding ones that actually
benefit from this power is becoming
quite a niche Endeavor you'll have to be
specifically looking for them and then
also you can have the most powerful chip
in the world but especially on Android
which is more often than not a victim of
lazy developer syndrome some apps are
just going to lag anyway so like I've
been playing a lot of Pokémon TCG pocket
recently it plays completely fine on the
latest iPhone 60 frames per second hell
it plays fine on an iPhone 12 but on the
2025 Flagship Samsung it lags I've
noticed this with the Amazon app it's
sloppily programmed I've noticed it with
zoom calls like the Android app is just
laggier and it seems to run the camera
in much worse quality the list goes on
my point being having this much power is
absolutely incredible but I don't think
the average person is going to notice
compared to the s24 ultra because most
of the bottl come down to software not
hardware and then there is the AI part
of the equation the majority of the
appeal of this s25 Ultra more so than
maybe any phone ever released is tied to
AI we've been told this AI is only free
till the end of 2025 but we still have
no idea how much the AI is going to cost
now I will say some of these new AI
features are amazing like AI select Game
Changer you know when someone sends you
a whole paragraph and you just want to
copy one sentence from that paragraph
This solves it or the ability to quickly
S screen grab something in a chat to
resurface it to the top so incredible
that I have mapped my AI select to come
up when I double tap the side button
hold to activate Gemini feels like a
real step up from Google Assistant they
finally figured out how to get Gemini to
do all the basic stuff that the
assistant was good at and so now the
focus is just in what ways can it go
further I think it still does need to go
further I mean I really wish it could be
a full phone assistant you know like
call me on Uber to the shops find me a
photo I took of Milo yesterday open the
new Captain America trailer on YouTube
it can't do any of those things right
now from the home screen but still at
least being able to now communicate with
complex commands like what's a great
restaurant in London for a group in
which one person has a penology one
person's a vegan and one person has
celiac disease yeah that's usually what
I'm working with I found vantra a
restaurant that caters to your group's
dietary needs and they are also mindful
of peanut allergies and you can see why
that is useful the ability to go one
step further and pull up Gemini live
with the context of what is on your
screen that feels even more Next Level
talk live about video oh never going to
give you up so tell me why did this
video become such a trend it's called
Rick Rolling and it's a classic internet
meme but why do you think this video
specifically became the meme you know
how sometimes the best memes are just so
Random I think that's a big part of it
it's catchy it's kind of goofy and that
element of surprise makes people laugh
that's actually the best answer I've had
so far from anyone now I haven't quite
figured out what exactly I'm going to do
with this capability on a regular basis
I guess most of what I watch on YouTube
is entertainment which you'd rather talk
about with another person instead of an
AI but let's say you were watching for
information you could see how it would
be a really good way to get a quick
summary of the video or to ask a
clarifying question that the video maybe
doesn't properly itself answer the AI
wallpaper generation is now probably the
best I've used on any phone it's fast it
gives you some very high quality options
that almost always look sharp on the
phone's display and I love the way that
the phone will instantly swap out the
rest of the user interfaces color
palette to match that said if you
actually want to bang a wallpaper you're
probably still better off hopping onto X
and just searching for it I feel like
the AI Generations they're like always
80% what you're looking for but they're
way less likely to be the 100% oh yeah
and the object eraser for photos is like
wow this is actually better in my
experience than even the one on the
Google pixel it really does make the
people and the objects in the background
of your shots feel like they are being
snapped out of existence now at the same
time some of these AI features are not
so good like all of these briefs that it
keeps giving me on my lock screen my
morning briefs are usually weather and
here's what's coming up later today on
my Google Calendar which sure okay I get
how that might be useful but if I want
my weather it is also on my home screen
and then my evening check-ins are like
even more weather which like I have a
roof why do I care when I'm about to go
to bed and then a reminder of today's
Google events but again it's not like
anyone's scheduling calls after 8:00
p.m. this stuff has already happened and
then tomorrow's Google events cross app
action the ability for two apps to
communicate with each other also needs a
couple of years in the oven I think but
even then I I just don't think there's
enough to it yet it's kind of as
predicted the level of intelligence
required to understand your request that
exists but the level of intelligence
required to understand the full context
that surrounds your request is missing
and without that it is practically
useless like for example you can say to
this phone when does the Pokémon popup
come to London add it to my calendar and
snap your fingers it's done title
location timing everything but the
Pokémon popup is open for four full days
so how did it decide that this is the
day that I'm going on and how did it
decide what time I'm going to be there
these are things that for this to be
actually useful it needs to truly
understand and to be able to run them by
me like a real personal system would the
Samsung now bar that sits on your lock
screen feels kind of like Apple's
Dynamic Island it's cool in concept it's
executed in a slick way but without
enough functionality or supported apps
to really have any impact on the way
that you use your phone like it's got
some very specific sports that if you're
into it can serve you up notifications
that show you current game progress but
like I'm not a massive Sports guy this
only starts to become useful to me at
the point where it can understand what
I'm interested in just generally so
let's say the fact that I open the
Pokémon card app once per day that's an
interest and then it can ping me when a
new expansion goes alive within that
game The Interpreter mode feels like in
moments there's a sparkle sometimes it
all just clicks and you're actually
having an almost real- time conversation
with someone in another language it's
just that the vast majority of cases are
more you see in real time on the screen
that it is completely butchered the
sentence that you're trying to say and
you're out there scurrying to hit the
stop button before it translates and you
accidentally tell the other person to
shave their cat oh yeah and then the
ability to record calls with the
additional perk to search through the
transcript afterwards and AI summarize
what you heard the seamless less and
presentation of this feature is pure
Superman it's just a shame that the
execution is closer to the Joker the
phone just does not seem to understand
what you're saying and if it doesn't
understand what's being said it doesn't
matter if you can search through it or
AI summarize it it's all gobbley and
separately but while we are on the
subject of dunking on this thing Samsung
did a little sneaky here they have
silently removed the Bluetooth
functionality of the S Pen so you can't
use it anymore to control your music
using air gestures or your camera
shutter can't say I ever really did much
of either of those but it's still not a
good look to see some things moving
backwards like this anyway my main point
was that yes there are still some
actually new actually great AI features
here it's just that with every single
one of them you have to put three pretty
large asterisks next to them like a some
of these features like Circle to search
and cross app action really they're
Google features so other phones will get
them too B A lot of the stuff will also
be coming to past Samsung phones via
updates and the biggest thing if all of
these features are so Central to this
s25 Ultra then how on Earth do we still
have absolutely no idea how much they're
going to cost us I'll tell you why
Samsung is in a very precarious position
here they were very quick to want to
take the crown for being the first
company to have ai they very much do not
want to be the first company to talk
about the downside that comes with that
AI do you remember the launch of the
Xbox One the single launch that you
could argue destroyed Xbox's entire
console business the company essentially
told people how they were going to
restrict the sharing of video games in
this generation of consoles how if I buy
one game that game becomes tied to my
account and I can't give or even lend it
to a friend and by revealing their
intention First Sony their key rival was
able to see that everyone responded
absolutely terribly to that decision to
realize that no one wanted anything to
do with this new Xbox because of it and
then all son he had to do was to step in
and tell people that to share discs on
the PlayStation you just had to hand it
from one person to the next in one Fell
Swoop the console war was practically
over and that is the exact situation
that Samsung is trying to avoid here
let's be honest every one of these
companies wants to charge you for AI but
if Samsung goes first then it leaves the
floor open for other companies to either
come in and charge way less than Samsung
to steal their Thunder or even just
straight up troll the company by keeping
theirs free for another year so I'm
convinced that Samsung is waiting for
someone else to say something but still
these guys withholding this information
is very much putting their business in
front of their users at this point less
than a year before they're saying that
you're about to be charged they should
be making it very clear how much and of
course then we've got the cameras and
I'd actually go as far as to say that
there are large improvements to the
cameras this year the s25 ultra does
take better Zoom photos than last year
it takes better Ultra wide shots it's
got better skin tones pretty much every
single image taken on every single lens
is sharper and the videos look cleaner
with less noise too not to mention that
it now shoots fast enough that I would
go as far as to say Samsung's 5 plus
year battle with shutter lag I'd say
it's finally put to bed I wouldn't say
this is the best phone camera ever I'd
say the iPhone is a little ahead the
Vivo X200 Pro is quite away ahead but
it's still top five again though to the
point that I'm making most of these
improvements have happened with without
any change to the camera Hardware from
last year so another one of the reasons
that I'm suggesting you might want to
wait this one out is to see if this
camera can get so much better without
changing the cameras then is this again
just software and are they going to
bring these improvements to their
previous phones I mean I'd say there's
at least a 50% chance that they don't
they might either decide that if we make
our old phones better no one's going to
buy the new ones or there's just a limit
to how much they can improve the last
ones because these improvements rest on
the more intelligent AI CES of the new
chipset so to bring this all together if
you're getting a new Android right now
and all you want is just to buy the best
phone there is then this is absolutely
one of the phones that you should be
looking at there's very little wrong
with it apart from some room for
improvement with the camera and some
wonky AI features but if you're looking
at it from the lens of value then it's
really hard to say that this phone is
better value than last year's phone
since most of the best things about it
are already on that phone coming to that
phone or should be coming to that phone
and a lot of the things that aren't are
going to be charged for so how can I say
say yes you should go out and buy this
before we know how much we're going to
be charged for to make the most of it oh
yeah and we can't forget the fastest way
to make friends and our sponsor surf
shark VPN because here's the thing
almost every single VPN has a cap you
might be able to share your login with
two people five people seven people with
Sur shark VPN one subscription gets VPN
access to you your buddies and your
entire city if you want it to it's the
most stable VPN I've used the app just
works whether you're on your phone or
your computer and it's one of the most
useful Swiss Army knif tools to have in
your back pocket it can make websites
that were previously misbehaving just
suddenly start working again it can let
you watch streaming content from other
countries it can make your computer
think you're back home even when you're
away somewhere so you don't have to keep
endlessly re authenticating your
accounts the list goes on all topped off
with the fact that the value proposition
has just gotten even better with the
code boss it's now $2 a month with an
extra 4 months for free and a 30-day
money back guarantee